hellforleathermagazine.com 2012-12-24

# Privacy Policy | Hell for Leather Hell for Leather

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for _Hell For Leather Magazine_ and Hell For Leather Media Free sites with free content. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to “Hell for Leather” include HellForLeatherMagazine.com and any and all other wholly owned subsidiaries or whole owned partner websites unless otherwise specified.

In this Privacy Policy, you will find answers to the following questions:

· **Which sites are covered by this policy?**  
· **What information do we gather about you?**  
· **What do we do with the information we gather about you?**  
· **What is our e-mail policy?**  
· **With whom do we share the information that we gather?**  
· **Disclosure to successors.**  
· **How do I change or update my personal information?**  
· **How do I opt-out from receiving promotional offers?**  
· **Is my information protected?**  
· **Other information: Compliance with legal process**  
· **Other information: Children’s Guidelines**  
· **Other information: Changes to this Privacy Policy**

**WHICH SITES ARE COVERED BY THIS POLICY?**  
This Privacy Policy applies to the following Hell For Leather Web sites:  
• _Hell For Leather Magazine_ (Free Content)

Please note, our Web sites may contain links to other Web sites for your convenience and information. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company before submitting your personal information.

**WHAT INFORMATION DO WE GATHER ABOUT YOU?**  
The information we gather falls into two categories: 1) Personally identifiable information, which includes personal information you voluntarily supply when you order, complete a survey, register for an online discussion, enter a contest or provide your e-mail address and 2) Non-personally identifiable information, which includes tracking information collected as you navigate through our sites.

**Personally Identifiable Information**  
HellForLeathermagazine.com may require that you supply certain personally identifiable information, including a unique e-mail address and demographic information (zip code, age, sex, household income (optional), job industry and job title) in order to complete certain transactions like purchasing from our store or verifying user submitted content. By using hellforleathermagazine.com, you are agreeing to our Terms of Service.

**Subscription Registration for our Web sites via Third-Party Tools**  
To help facilitate HellForLeatherMagazine.com subscriptions, we have partnered with PayPal to gather subscription information and fees. Subscription and registration through PayPal is governed by their privacy policy and terms of use which can be viewed on [PayPal’s site](https://cms.paypal.com/us/cgi-bin/marketingweb?cmd=_render-content&content_ID=ua/Legal_Hub_full&locale.x=en_US). _Hell For Leather Magazine_ is not responsible for the privacy policy of PayPal and encourages you to read their privacy policy before supplying any personal information. Hell For Leather is not responsible for any actions PayPal relating to personal information you have supplied to PayPal. PayPal will be providing us with any subscriber information you have provided in connection with your subscription purchase. Information supplied to us will be governed by this privacy policy.

**Paid Products and Services**  
Some of our products are sold through third party vendors and are governed by their privacy policies. Hell For Leather is not responsible for the privacy policies of third party vendors and encourages you to read their policies before signing up. Additionally, by making a purchase of Hell For Leather products or services through a third party vendor, you expressly grant permission through your action for Hell For Leather to share any personal information with that vendor. Some of our products are sold internally through parent company Hell For Leather Media or wholly or partially owned subsidiaries and are thus governed by this privacy policy. By making a purchase from Hell For Leather directly, Hell For Leather still reserves the right to share your personal information with third parties for the strict purposes of processing payments, collections on delinquent payments, or disputes with credit card companies, banks, or third party payment transfer services with whom you have used to make a payment to Hell For Leather.

**Contests, Sweepstakes and Special Offers**  
On occasion, Hell For Leather collects personal information from readers in connection with optional sweepstakes, contests or special offers. If this information is to be shared with a third party other than Hell For Leather, we will notify you at the time of collection. If you do not want any personal information shared, you may always decline to participate in the sweepstakes, contest or special offer.

**Surveys and Market Research**  
Hell For Leather may collect personal information from readers in connection with voluntary surveys. Data may be collected on our Web sites, on the phone or through the mail. The information you provide in answer to optional survey questions may be shared, but only in the aggregate, with advertisers and partners unless we notify you otherwise at the time of collection.  
All survey data is reported and/or used in aggregate form only, and no personally identifiable information is released. From time to time, we may use different technologies, including cookies, to better understand answers to our surveys. As a panel member, we require that you supply us with your e-mail address and name. Home address and telephone number are optional.

**Special Events and Promotions**  
We often receive information regarding readers who may attend Hell For Leather Special Events and Promotions. Such information will be used as indicated at the time of collection.

**Links**  
The Hell For Leather Site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Hell for Leather is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Hell for Leather.

**Non-personally Identifiable Information**  
In addition to personally identifiable information, we also collect certain non-personally identifiable information through technology and tools, including cookies, Web Beacons and log data. We aggregate and analyze this information in order to learn more about how our Web sites are used.

**Cookies from Us**  
As is standard practice on many Web sites, we use “cookies” and other technologies to recognize you and provide personalization, as well as to help us understand, where our visitors are going and how much time they spend there. You will not be able to access certain areas of our Web sites, including HellForLeatherMagazine.com, if your computer does not accept cookies from us.

**Third Party Cookies**  
Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, Hell for Leather has no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Hell For Leather only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons)**  
HellForLeatherMagazine.com or its Business Partners may elect to use a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/action tags/pixel tags), alone or in conjunction with cookies, to better manage our site and the information gathered. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. Clear gifs may alert HellForLeatherMagazine.com’s server about the online movements of Web users. The main difference between cookies and clear gifs is that clear gifs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Please keep in mind that we do not have access to any information collected by the clear gifs used by Hell For Leather’s Business Partners nor any additional related information.

**Analytics Technologies**  
We reserve the right to change the vendors who provide us with usage data.

**IP Addresses**  
Hell For Leather logs Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, or the location of your computer on the Internet, for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes. We use this information in an aggregate fashion to track access to our Web sites.

**Log Files**  
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. We may use a tracking utility that uses log files to analyze user movement.

_WHAT DO WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE GATHER ABOUT YOU?_

**Statistical Analysis**  
Hell For Leather may perform statistical, demographic and marketing analyses of users, and their browsing and purchasing patterns, for product development purposes and to generally inform advertisers about the nature of our readers. We also use such information to allow advertising to be targeted, in aggregate, to the users for whom such advertising is most pertinent. HellForLeatherMagazine.com may share personal information with Hell For Leather Media or any other wholly owned subsidiary of Hell For Leather for analysis purposes, including analysis to improve customer relationships.

**Products and Services from Hell For Leather**  
From time to time, we may provide readers with information and offers about other products and services offered by Hell For Leather, including premium products and services. This information will only be shared internally.

**User Generated Content (Including Comments and Reviews)**  
We offer opportunities for you to engage in public activities on HellForLeatherMagazine.com, including submitting comments, recommendations, reader reviews and ratings in a number of areas. Any information you disclose in your submissions, along with your screen name or ID, or any image or photo, becomes public and may be used by Hell For Leather for online and offline promotional or commercial uses in any and all media. If you chose to engage in public activities on the site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these areas, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

**EMail Newsletters**  
If you choose to receive them, Hell For Leather will periodically send you e-mail newsletters or promotional e-mail about services offered by Hell for Leather and its advertisers.

**WHAT IS OUR E-MAIL POLICY?**  
Hell for Leather complies fully with the federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your e-mail address without your permission. If you feel you have received an e-mail from us in error, please contact [info@rideapart.com](mailto:info@rideapart.com).

**Account and Service-Related Email**  
Hell For Leather reserves the right to send you e-mail relating to your account status. This includes order confirmations, renewal/expiration notices, notices of credit-card problems, other transactional e-mails and notifications about major changes to our Web sites and/or to our Privacy Policy. If you have registered for online discussions or other services, you may receive e-mail specific to your participation in those activities.

**Promotional Email**  
If you choose to receive them, Hell for Leather may periodically e-mail you messages about products and services that we think may be of interest to you. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by following the “unsubscribe” instructions located near the bottom of each e-mail.  
From time to time, Hell For Leather may obtain e-mail addresses from third party sources to be used for promotional e-mails. You can choose not to receive messages in the future by following the “unsubscribe” instructions located near the bottom of each e-mail.

**Survey Email**  
We may send you an e-mail inviting you to participate in user surveys, asking for feedback on HellForLeatherMagazine.com and existing or prospective products and services, as well as information to better understand our users. User surveys greatly help us to improve our Web site, and any information we obtain in such surveys will not be shared with third parties, except in aggregate form.

**Emails From You**  
If you send us e-mails, you should be aware that information disclosed in e-mails may not be secure or encrypted and thus may be available to others. We suggest that you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal or confidential information in e-mails. We will use your e-mail address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

**Email This Article Feature**  
HellForLeatherMagazine.com readers may use this feature to e-mail links to articles (or other content such as slideshows). The e-mail addresses that you supply to this service are saved for your convenience for future articles you may wish to e-mail; these addresses are not used for any other purpose, and will not be shared with any third parties.

**WITH WHOM DO WE SHARE THE INFORMATION THAT WE GATHER?**  
_Hell For Leather_  
Hell For Leather will not sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your e-mail address or any information that personally identifies you without your permission. We do, however, share information about our audience in aggregate form.  
_Service Providers_  
We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, including credit-card and billing processing, shipping, e-mail distribution, list processing and analytics or promotions management. We provide these companies only with the information they need to perform their services. These service providers are restricted from using this data in any way other than to provide services for Hell For Leather, and they may not share or resell this data.  
We reserve the right to disclose your opt-out information to third parties so they can suppress your name from future solicitations, in accordance with applicable laws. We may occasionally release personal information as required by law, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena. (For more information, see the “Compliance with legal process” section of this policy.)  
Business Transitions In the event Hell for Leather goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of a portion of its assets, users’ personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred.

**DISCLOSURE TO SUCCESSORS**  
We may disclose your Personal Information to any successor-in-interest of ours, such as a company that acquires us. In the event Hell For Leather goes through a business transition, such as a merger or acquisition by or with another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your Personal Information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email or by a notice on our Website of any such change in ownership or control of your Personal Information.

**HOW DO I CHANGE OR UPDATE MY PERSONAL INFORMATION?**  
Information collected in conjunction with purchasing a subscription package is collected via PayPal. Changes to information used to purchase subscriptions should be made through [PayPal’s website](https://www.paypal.com/). To update any other personal information, for example information used to generate user content, please contact us at info@hellforleathermagazine.com.

**HOW DO I OPT-OUT FROM RECEIVING PROMOTIONAL OFFERS?**  
_E-mail Promotions_  
If, at any time, you prefer not to receive e-mail marketing information from us, simply follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of each e-mail.  
If you experience difficulty with the unsubscribe process, feel free to contact us at [info@rideapart.com](mailto:info@rideapart.com) and provide your e-mail address along with the name of the newsletter from which you would like to unsubscribe.  
_Offline Promotions_  
If, at any time, you prefer not to receive traditional mail or telephone solicitations originated by Hell For Leather and its third party affiliates, please e-mail us at [info@rideapart.com](mailto:info@rideapart.com)

**IS MY INFORMATION PROTECTED?**  
Data Security: To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect the information we collect online. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

**OTHER INFORMATION: Compliance with Legal Process**  
We may disclose personal information if we are required to do so by law or we in good faith believe that such action is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process; (2) protect and defend our rights and property; (3) protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our Web sites; or (4) protect the personal safety or property of our users or the public (among other things, this means that if you provide false information or attempt to pose as someone else, information about you may be disclosed as part of any investigation into your actions).

**OTHER INFORMATION: Children’s Guidelines**  
COPPA Compliance: Hell For Leather does not knowingly collect or store any personal information, even in aggregate, about children under the age of 13.

**OTHER INFORMATION: Changes to This Policy**  
This Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time. Any such changes will be posted on this page. If we make a significant or material change in the way we use your personal information, the change will be posted on this page thirty (30) days prior to taking effect and registered users will be notified via e-mail.

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us by email at [info@ridepart.com](mailto:info@ridepart.com).
